Dr Victor Maus

Senior Researcher

Curriculum Vitae Oktober 2021 **♀** Welthandelsplatz 1, 1020 Vienna, Austria

Münster Germany

☆ victor-maus.com↓ +43 1 31336 6176✓ vwmaus1@gmail.com

@victor_mausvwmaus

in victor-maus-083a79191 G wN2LseQAAAAJ&hl d 0000-0002-7385-4723

I am a researcher in Geoinformatics and Spatial Data Science for sustainable development, in particular related to land-use changes. I am the author of Time-Weighted Dynamic Time Warping (TWDTW) algorithm, to classify Earth observation time series in data-scarce conditions. I have implemented the TWDTW as open-source in my R package dtwSat. I have also led the production of the first-ever spatially-explicit global assessment of mining land use to assess the environmental impacts and sustainability of the global mining sector.

EDUCATION

2016	PhD in Earth System Science National Institute for Space Research (INPE)	São José dos Campos, Brazil
2011	MSc in Computational Modeling Federal University of Juiz de Fora (UFJF)	Juiz de Fora, Brazil
2009	BSc in Environmental Engineering Franciscan University (UFN)	Santa Maria, Brazil

CURRENT POSITIONS

2018-Today	Senior Researcher	Vienna, Austria
	Vienna University of Economics and Business (WU)	
2016-Today	Research Scholar	Laxenburg, Austria
	International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis (IIASA)	

PREVIOUS POSITIONS

Research Assistant

2014-2016

2014 2010	University of Münster (WWU)	Mulister, Germany
2012-2014	University Lecturer Federal University of Pampa (UNIPAMPA)	Itaqui, Brazil
2011-2012	Research Assistant National Institute for Space Research (INPE)	São José dos Campos, Brazil
2009-2011	Research Assistant Federal University of Juiz de Fora (UFJF)	Juiz de Fora, Brazil

AWARDS RESEARCH GRANTS FELLOWSHIPS

2014-2016	Research Assistant University of Münster (WWU)	Münster, Germany
2012-2014	University Lecturer Federal University of Pampa (UNIPAMPA)	Itaqui, Brazil
2011-2012	Research Assistant National Institute for Space Research (INPE)	São José dos Campos, Brazil
2009-2011	Research Assistant Federal University of Juiz de Fora (UFJF)	Juiz de Fora, Brazil

SUPERVISION OF STUDENTS

 esearch Assistant niversity of Münster (WWU)	Münster, Germany
niversity Lecturer ederal University of Pampa (UNIPAMPA)	Itaqui, Brazil
 esearch Assistant ational Institute for Space Research (INPE)	São José dos Campos, Brazil
 esearch Assistant ederal University of Juiz de Fora (UFJF)	Juiz de Fora, Brazil

TEACHING ACTIVITIES INSTITUTIONAL RESPONSIBILITIES REVIEWING ACTIVITIES PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Luckeneder, S., Giljum, S., Schaffartzik, A., **Maus, V**., & Tost, M. (2021). Surge in global metal mining threatens vulnerable ecosystems. *Global Environmental Change*, 69, 102303. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gloenvcha.2021. 102303
- 2. Maus, V., Giljum, S., Gutschlhofer, J., Silva, D. M. da, Gass, S. L. B., Luckeneder, S., Lieber, M., & McCallum, I. (2020). A global-scale data set of mining areas. *Scientific Data*, 7(1), 289. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-020-00624-w
- 3. Bruckner, M., Wood, R., Moran, D., Kuschnig, N., Wieland, H., **Maus, V.**, & Börner, J. (2019). FABIO-the construction of the food and agriculture biomass input-output model. *Environmental Science & Technology*, *53*(19), 11302–11312. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.9b03554
- 4. Stanimirova, R., Arévalo, P., Kaufmann, R. K., **Maus, V.**, Lesiv, M., Havlík, P., & Friedl, M. A. (2019). Sensitivity of global pasturelands to climate variation. *Earth's Future*. https://doi.org/10.1029/2019EF001316
- 5. Maus, V., Câmara, G., Appel, M., & Pebesma, E. (2019). dtwSat: Time-Weighted Dynamic Time Warping for Satellite Image Time Series Analysis in R. *Journal of Statistical Software*, 88(5), 1–31. https://doi.org/10.18637/jss.v088.i05
- 6. Bruckner, M., Häyhä, T., Giljum, S., **Maus, V.**, Fischer, G., Tramberend, S., & Börner, J. (2019). Quantifying the global cropland footprint of the european union's non-food bioeconomy. *Environmental Research Letters*, 14(4), 045011. https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ab07f5
- 7. Hadi, Krasovskii, A., **Maus, V.**, Yowargana, P., Pietsch, S., & Rautiainen, M. (2018). Monitoring Deforestation in Rainforests Using Satellite Data: A Pilot Study from Kalimantan, Indonesia. *Forests*, *9*(7). https://doi.org/10.3390/f9070389
- 8. See, L., Laso Bayas, J. C., Schepaschenko, D., Perger, C., Dresel, C., Maus, V., Salk, C., Weichselbaum, J., Lesiv, M., McCallum, I., Moorthy, I., & Fritz, S. (2017). LACO-Wiki: A New Online Land Cover Validation Tool Demonstrated Using GlobeLand30 for Kenya. *Remote Sensing*, 9(7). https://doi.org/10.3390/rs9070754
- 9. Furlan, V. J. M., **Maus, V**., Batista, I., & Bandarra, N. M. (2017). Production of docosahexaenoic acid by Auranti-ochytrium sp. ATCC PRA-276. *Brazilian Journal of Microbiology*, 48(2), 359–365. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bjm. 2017.01.001
- 10. **Maus, V.**, Camara, G., Cartaxo, R., Sanchez, A., Ramos, F. M., & Queiroz, G. R. de. (2016). A time-weighted dynamic time warping method for land-use and land-cover mapping. *IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Applied Earth Observations and Remote Sensing*, *9*(8), 3729–3739. https://doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2016.2517118
- 11. Furlan, V. J. M., Castelo Paulo, M. do, **Maus, V**., Ferreira, J., Batista, I., & Bandarrac, N. M. (2016). Production of docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) from Thraustochytrium sp. ATCC 26185 using different nitrogen concentrations. *Boletim Centro de Pesquisa de Processamento de Alimentos*, 34(2), 1–11. https://doi.org/10.5380/cep.v34i2. 53189
- See, L., Schepaschenko, D., Lesiv, M., McCallum, I., Fritz, S., Comber, A., Perger, C., Schill, C., Zhao, Y., Maus, V., Siraj, M. A., Albrecht, F., Cipriani, A., Vakolyuk, M., Garcia, A., Rabia, A. H., Singha, K., Marcarini, A. A., Kattenborn, T., ... Obersteiner, M. (2015). Building a hybrid land cover map with crowdsourcing and geographically weighted regression. *ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing*, 103, 48–56. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2014.06.016
- 13. **Maus, V.**, Costa, A. B. da, & Righes, A. A. (2009). Tratamento do lixiviado de aterro de resíduos sólidos urbanos por processo fenton. *Tecno-Lógica*, 13(1), 52–59. https://doi.org/10.17058/tecnolog.v13i1.931